A Guide to the Hughes family Papers, 1776-1928
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Hughes family Papers, 1776-1928
Library of Virginia
37070
1.25 cu. ft. plus 1 oversize folder
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from Virginia Department of Treasury, 18 January 2000.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Hughes family were residents of South Carolina. Simon P. Hughes (1844-1904) graduated from Newberry College (S.C.) in 1873 and attended Lutheran Theological Southern Seminary (S.C.), 1873-1876. In 1876 he was ordained a minister and became pastor of Lutheran Chapel, Newberry, South Carolina, in 1879. Hughes moved to Williamsport, Pennsylvania in 1881 to serve as pastor of St. Paul's Lutheran Congregation. In 1891 Hughes resigned his Williamsport pastorate and moved to Red Hook, New York. The Hughes family returned to Williamsport, a few years later, where Hughes served as pastor of St. Luke's Congregation.
Hughes married Elizabeth Hancock (b. 1853) of Kingston, Pennsylvania, in 1886, and they had two children: Elizabeth Denison Hughes (1888-1918), married to Colonel Hope, and Emily Hancock Hughes (b. 1893), married to Donald Taylor Hunter of Hampton, Virginia. Elizabeth Hancock Hughes was descended from the Denison family of Conneticut and John Howland (d. ca. 1670), a pilgram on the Mayflower. After Simon's death, Elizabeth Hughes relocated to Virginia Beach, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1776-1928, including certificates, clippings, correspondence, diplomas, pamphlets, literary manuscripts, and photographs. The majority of the papers relate to Simon P. Hughes and his wife, Elizabeth Hancock Hughes, when they resided in Pennsylvania. The collection contains genealogical research notes on the Denison, Hancock, and Howland families, by Elizabeth Hughes, and an application for membership to the Daughters of the American Revolution. The collection also contains a memorial of Simon Hughes, and Elizabeth Hughes' diaries of her honeymoon travels in Europe, May-August 1886. The correspondence consists mainly of letters to Simon Hughes regarding family, health and religious matters. Of note are two letters, dated 1878, from Henry W. Longfellow, Cambridge, Massachusettes, to Simon Hughes.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Calling cards, nd (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Certificates, 1848-1893 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Clippings, 1895-1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Clippings, nd (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1878-1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Currency, 1776-1866 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Diaries, Travel, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Diaries, Travel, Summary, 18886 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Drawings, nd (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Envelopes, 1899-1920 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Execution, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Financial records, 1907-1928 (Folder 12)
- Genealogy, 1898-1918 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Hughes, Emily, 1898-1903 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Literary manuscripts, nd (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Memorial, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous, 1870-1898 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Notes, 1925, nd (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Pamphlets, 1900-1916 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Photographs, ca. 1860-1900 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Photographs, ca. 1860-1926 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Postcards, nd (Box 2, Folder 7)
- St. Paul's Church (Williamsport, Pa.), 1899 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Bibles, 1871 (Box 3)
- Ephemera, nd (Box 3)
- Oversized: Certificates, diplomas, photograph, 1851-1903